Cristina Amico

Dublin, Ireland

Email: mariacristina.amico@gmail.com
Portfolio: https://criamico.github.io

Linkedin: https://linkedin.com/in/cristinaamico

Github: https://github.com/criamico

Role

Front-end Developer

Summary

I'm an automation engineer who embraced software development as a way to express my technical interests and my creativity at the same time.

So far in my career I had the chance to experiment many different technologies and approaches. I've worked in two different countries and for several companies, thus I've got to know different work environments, from the small and agile company to the large and multicultural corporate environment. On every job I've acquired something, either new and interesting technical skills or great human experiences. My goal is to keep learning.

In particular, while working at FCA main offices in Detroit, I developed a deep interest for UI development. After this two-years experience, ended when I relocated to Dublin for personal reasons, I started to use my skills on web UI development.

My personal portfolio is visible at https://criamico.github.io.

Experience

UI Developer at *FCA North America LLC* (formerly Chrysler Corporation) May 2013 - June 2015 — Auburn Hills, MI, USA

Responsible of the UI software development for the 7" instrument cluster panel of FCA new vehicles.

- UI implemented via the Altia suite, using provided requirements, graphical assets, fonts and localization files.
- Implementing innovative proof-of-concept projects not targeted for production
- Experience in working and communicating with different stakeholders to define and clarify project requirements: UI / graphics designers, UX team, product engineers and suppliers.
- Automated post-processing of graphical assets
- Managing and implementing Change Requests
- Handling and fixing tracked bugs issued by QA teams
- Experience in creating prototype wireframes / UI mockups and collaborating with graphics designers to improve the final aspect and behavior of the software
- Ability to work on deadlines and to handle several projects at the time by self-managing priorities
- Experience in attending periodic code reviews
- Accomplishments
- Successfully delivered code for several production vehicles, such as:
- 2015 Dodge Challenger, 2015 Dodge Charger, 2015 Chrysler 300, Maserati Ghibli, Maserati Quattroporte, Maserati Levante

 Pictures of the actual clusters are visible at http://www.drivesrt.com/2015/challenger-srt-hellcat/gallery/

Software Developer at ACTIA ITALIA S.r.L.

May 2011 - July 2012 — Turin, Italy

- UI & sw development for telematics devices
- Development of data processing algorithms to save and store statistical data obtained from multiple sensors (pressure sensors, strain gauges) connected to display-equipped telematics devices
- Development of a Python-based parser to automatically generate spreadsheets reports from multiple csv files

Electronic Systems Engineer at *CNH Industrial* (formerly Iveco S.p.A.) Oct 2009 - Apr 2010 — Turin, Italy

- Testing and validation of engine ECUs software through an "hardware in the loop" equipment to simulate the vehicle behavior.
- Requirements analysis
- Test cases writing and execution.

Intern at Department of industrial and Mechanical Engineering of Università di Catania

Oct 2009 - Apr 2010 — Catania, Italy

- Development of a C# numerical software aimed to calculate natural frequencies of any parallel robot (PKM) described by its joints, improving an existing Matlab algorithm.
- Dissertation titled: "Implementation of a C# algorithm to study the elastodynamics of parallel robots".

Intern at *INGV* (Italian National Institute of Geophysics and Volcanology) May 2009 - Oct 2009 — Catania, Italy

Design and implementation of an image processing algorithm aimed to quickly process multiple archive videos.

Goal: automatically detect and count the explosions recorded in historic footage of the Stromboli volcano; Implemented as a Labview-based tool

Continuing Education

FreeCodeCamp Front-end certification

April 2016 - current

My progress status is visible at https://www.freecodecamp.com/criamico

Udacity Front-end Web Developer Path

Jul 2015 - current

Online courses focused on front-end web development.

Education

Master's Degree in Automation Engineering

2006 - 2010 — Università degli Studi di Catania, 95125 Catania (CT), Italy

Bachelor's Degree in Electronic Engineering

Skills

Communication and interpersonal skills

- Good verbal & written communication skills
- Excellent team work experience acquired in a large and multi-cultural workplace environment
- Ability to quickly adapt to new environments

Technical and job-related skills

- Excellent attention to details
- Strong analytical and problem solving skills
- Self-driven and able to meet deadlines

Software skills

Web technologies:

- HTML5, CSS3, SASS
- Javascript
- JQuery, AngularJS 1.x
- Bootstrap
- Jasmine
- npm
- Responsive web design

Code versioning:

GIT

Graphics:

- Photoshop CS6, GIMP
- Inkscape
- UX & Usability (work experience)

Other programming languages and tools

• C, Python, Matlab

Db:

SQLite

Methodologies

• Agile, TDD

Languages

English, Italian (mother tongue)

Interests

- Reading
- Travelling